MATTHEW MCKAY

Front-End Web Developer

416-271-2613

matthewmckay@gmail.com

GitHub

0

Toronto, Ontario

B

matthewmckay.com

in

LinkedIn

WEB DEVELOPER PROFILE

Greetings! I am a Toronto-based front-end web developer with expertise in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, and React. Previously, I owned and operated a construction company for nearly 15 years, during which I developed valuable soft skills. Seeking a change, I transitioned to a new career in the tech industry, which had long been an interest of mine. Today, I've traded in my tool belt for a keyboard and am building responsive, accessible, and user-friendly websites instead of homes.

SKILLS SUMMARY

- · JavaScript Libraries and Frameworks
- React
- SASS
- · Paired Programming
- · Problem Solving

- · RESTful APIs & Firebase
- HTML5 & CSS3
- Technical Documentation
- · Team Collaboration
- · Critical Thinking

- · Responsive Design
- Git & GitHub
- · Web Accessibility
- · Project Scope Management
- · Time Management

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

Juno College - Project 4 - Quiz Game: What do YOU no? <Live><Repo>

React | FireBase | APIs | HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JSX | Git | GitHub

- Worked with a group of developers and multiple third-party APIs to retrieve and manipulate object data to accomplish goal
 of creating quiz game requiring users to match homonyms with their definitions
- Gained experience working efficiently and effectively with three other developers in an agency environment, delivering a fully functional product on a timeline, while collaborating on Zoom, Slack and GitHub

Juno College - Project 3 - Rijks Museum Art Search <Live><Repo>

React | APIs | HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JSX | Git | GitHub

 Made multiple API calls using core React concepts to create a dynamic website allowing users to discover world renown art using multiple search input methods

Juno College - Project 2 - Horoscope 4 U <<u>Live</u>><<u>Repo></u>

APIs | HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | SASS | Git | GitHub

• Displayed competency in working with third-party APIs, DOM manipulation, JavaScript, error handling and UI design, and proficiency in pair programming, coordination and communication

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Juno College of Technology (formerly HackerYou) | Web Development Immersive Bootcamp Certificate | Toronto | 2022 University of Toronto | Hons. Bachelor of Science in Human Biology | Fine Art History Minor | Toronto Centennial College | Journalism Diploma | Toronto

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Contractor | DCD Construction | Self-Employed | Greater Toronto Area

Jan 2008 - Sep 2022

- As an apprentice of DCD Construction, worked directly under general contractor in large residential and commercial projects
 providing clients with excellent customer service, communication and execution of 15-20 projects per year
- As a business owner of own contracting business, took on more complex projects as experience increased, while surpassing revenue goals year over year by over 50%
- Worked with clients to manage their project expectations via daily timeline updates, revised designs and budgets, while
 providing excellent customer service to accomplish their renovation goals
- Designed, developed and implemented company's marketing plan through website, flyers and business cards
- · Used latest accounting software to stay updated on finances, identify areas of savings and maximize revenue and tax returns
- Responded to and resolved emergency situations, including unexpected structural damage and flooding

Volunteer | Hennick Bridgepoint Hospital | Ambulatory Care Gym

May 2019 - Mar 2020

- · Helped physiotherapists rehabilitate knee replacement patients through set up, clean up, patient interaction in therapy gym
- Assisted and escorted patients as needed while at therapy gym and pool

Public Address Announcer | University of Toronto | St. George Campus

Sep 2004 - Apr 2015

- Hosted hundreds of University of Toronto varsity-level hockey, volleyball, basketball, football and figure skating events
- Worked with and trained U of T staff and students to deliver timely in-game announcements and increase audience
 engagement and entertainment
- Worked national sporting events such as the CIS national championships in hockey, volleyball and soccer, which included
 opening ceremonies, all sporting events and award presentations